

Julio Cesar Ramirez Paredes

Profile

Bachelor of civil engineering, expert in engineering solutions for fluid mechanics and computational fluid dynamics in challenging problems. Interest in fluid mechanics and programming languages. Outstanding learning capacity, motivation to continue learning and orientation to achieve results in my career.

Social Network

Mz. C1 Lt. 26

- Mario Cavagnaro Bellavista, Callao
- J (+51) 939196012
- ✓ julio.ramirez@pucp.edu.pe
- in Linkedin
- Github
- Pucp
- **@** Website
- 2 Resume

Languages

English Portuguese

Programming

C++ Fortran Python

EDUCATION

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering

San Miguel ,PE Jul 2019

Work Experience

Hidro Mayu

Lambayeque, PE

Structural equipment installation assistant

Mar 2023

• Mechanics of materials and structural analysis: Training to teachers about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional Pedro Ruiz Gallo's structural engineering laboratory

Hidro Mayu

Huacho, PE

Hydraulic equipment maintenance support

Nov 2022

- o Fluid mechanics and open channel hydraulics: Maintenance and training to teachers and students about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional José Faustino Sánchez Carrión's hydraulics laboratory
- Centro de Investigación y Tecnología del Agua Barranco, PE Research Assistant Sep 2019 - Nov 2021
 - o Urban air quality: Numerical simulation of the navier equations for incompresible newtonian flow in air fluid in urban environments using Openfoam.
 - Dam break: Numerical modeling of the shallow water equation for incompresible newtonian flow in dam break escenarios using Telemac-2D.
- Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnologia

Barranco, PE

CFD Direct 2021

CFD Support 2019

Laboratory 2018

Centro de Cómputo

UNIMASTER 2018

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021

- o Mathematics III: Solid understanding of linear algebra and numerical
- Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú San Miguel, PE Mar 2019 - Jul 2020 Jefe de Práctica
 - o Open Channel Hydraulics: Solid understading of channel morphology, hydraulic engineering and sediment transport.
 - MJ & Asociados Water Resources Consulting Lima, PE Practicing civil engineer Mar 2019 - Jun 2019
 - River flood: Observation of flood zone in the Moquegua river under extreme flood condition to investigate the resilience of the infrastructure.

Courses

Master python for data science inLearning 2021

Programming CFD OpenFOAM

Fire modelling with OpenFOAM OpenFOAM 2020

OpenFOAM advanced

OpenFOAM turbulence CFD Support 2019

Open source hydraulics modelling of shal-

Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería Hydraulics low water flow

Autocad 2018 advanced

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C++, C, Fortran, Python, R, Javascript, Scilab, Matlab, CSS, HTML, Bash y Lisp.
- Softwares: Hecras, Telemac, Flo-2D, River2D, OpenFOAM, Qgis, Arcgis, Emacs, Pointwise, Tecplot, Blender, Autocad, Latex, Ubuntu, Git y Aws.
- **Tiping**: Typing speed of 65 wpm Monkeytype, Keybr.